Guide to the Lisa Fox and Curt Royston Papers 1980-1987 MSS 249
Fales Library and Special Collections
Lisa Fox and Curt Royston Papers
1980-87
MSS 249
Fales Library and Special Collections
4.0 cubic feet
Fox, Lisa
Royston, Curt
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival collections.
Arrangement
The collections is organized into five series based on format.
Series I: Paper and Photographs
Series II: Posters
Series III: Film
Series IV: Video recordings
Series V: Sound recordings
Related Material at Fales Library and Special Collections
Curt Royston Papers
Biographical Note
Curt Royston is best known for his proficiency in a variety of media: painting, sculpture, photography, film, and video, and often in combination. His work has been shown extensively throughout the United States and Europe including a 1987 one-man exhibition at the Whitney Museum of American Art. Lisa Fox was a leading dancer with the Merce Cunningham Dance Company from 1976-1980 and has been a choreographer with Lisa Fox Danse for over thirty years. Together Royston and Fox collaborated on a series of multimedia installations, as well as a number of 16mm dance-based films throughout the 1980s, the most popular of which is "In Artificial Light" (1983).
Scope and Content
This collection contains reviews, photographs, transparencies, posters, video and film related to the multimedia collaborations of Lisa Fox and Curt Royston.
Fox, Lisa; Royston, Curt
- Series I: Paper and Photographs
  - "In Artificial Light", undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Reviews, 1987-88 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - [Transparencies, High Noon], undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series II: Posters
  - Lisa Fox, Danse, Salle Simon I. Patino, Cite Universitaire de Geneve, February 8, [19--] (Map-case 4.E)
  - The Kitchen USA Touring, June 14-15, [19--] (Map-case 4.E)
- Series III: Film
  - Subseries A: Access Copies
    Conditions Governing Access
    Access Copies may not be available for all material. Please consult a Fales Archivist.
    - In Artificial Light, a film by Curt Royston (2010 Restoration Print), 1982 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 249.0094)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
      Gauge: 16mm
      Color, Sound
      Duration: 20 minutes
  - Subseries B: Originals
    - Hothouse (title on print), undated (Box 2, Media ID: 249.0001)
      Length: 400 ft
    - Hothouse, 1985 (Box 3, Media ID: 249.0002)
    - Hothouse - 2nd Answer Print, undated (Box 3, Media ID: 249.0003)
    - In Artificial Light, undated (Box [1], Media ID: 249.0004)
      Length:700 ft
    - In Artificial Light - Mag Track, undated (Box [1], Media ID: 249.0005)
    - Puss and Boots, c.a. 1980 (Box 2, Media ID: 249.0006)
      Length:100 ft
    - Kitchen Show on the Staten Island Ferry, c.a. 1981 (Box 2, Media ID: 249.0007)
    - Notes for an Adagio, undated (Box 2, Media ID: 249.0008)
      Length:260 ft
    - Notes for an Adagio - Pix, c.a. 1982 (Box 2, Media ID: 249.0009)
    - White Shirt Place - Reel 1 - Mag Track, undated (Box 3, Media ID: 249.0010)
      Length:850 ft
    - White Shirt Place - Reel 2 - Mag Track, undated (Box 3, Media ID: 249.0011)
      Length:650 ft
    - In Artificial Light, undated (Box [1], Media ID: 249.0012)
      Length:670 ft
    - Hot House, undated (Box 3, Media ID: 249.0013)
      Length:450 ft
    - En Passant, undated (Box 3, Media ID: 249.0014)
      Length:500 ft
    - Notes for an Adagio, undated (Box 2, Media ID: 249.0015)
      Length:140 ft
- Series IV: Video recordings
  Open to researchers. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival collections.
  Some audiovisual materials have not been preserved and are currently available to researchers.
  - "High Noon in Half Light", undated (Box 5, Media ID: 249.0016)
    Original format: 1in
    Duration: 33 minutes
    Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  - "High Noon in Half Light", undated (Box 5, Media ID: 249.0017)
  - "High Noon in Half Light", undated (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0018)
    Existence and Location of Copies note
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0041.
    Original format: 3/4in Umatic
  - "High Noon in Half Light", undated (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0019)
    Original format: VHS
  - High Noon in Half Light: "Eye Light" Camera #1, November 10, 1987 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0020)
    Duration: unknown
    General note
    Alternate Title: "High Noon in Half Light"
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0044
  - Half Light "All Our Hands" Camera #1, November 10, 1987 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0021)
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0047.
  - Half Light - "Eye Light" Camera #2, November 17, 1987 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0022)
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0050
  - Half Light - "All Our Hands" Camera #2, November 17, 1987 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0023)
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0053.
  - Half Light - "Blue Room" Camera #2, November 17, 1987 (Box 4, Media ID:249.0024)
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0056.
  - "Eye Light" Performance #3, November 28, 1987 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0025)
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0059.
  - "All Our Hands" Performance #3, November 28, 1987 (Box [1], Media ID: 249.0026)
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0062.
  - "Blue Room" Performance #3, November 28, 1987 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0027)
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0065.
  - Overhead Cam Performance #3, November 28, 1987 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0028)
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0068.
  - "In Artificial Light", undated (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0029)
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0071.
  - "In Artificial Light", January 1983 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0030)
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0097
  - Downtown Madonna Part 2 and "In Artificial Light", undated (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0031)
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0074.
    Original format: Betacam SP
  - "In Artificial Light", undated (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0032)
    Format: VHS
    Duration: [unknown]
  - "Hot House", undated (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0033)
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0077.
    Duration: 10 minutes
  - "Hot House" - Original film to video transfer, undated (Box 5, Media IDL 249.0034)
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0080
  - Lisa Fox "Floored", Kitchen Performance 12/10/81, December 10, 1981 (Box 5, Media ID: 249.0035)
    Format: 3/4in Umatic
    Duration: 00:40:00
  - Lisa Fox "The Feast", January 1983 (Box 5, Media ID: 249.0036)
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0083
    Duration: 8 minutes
  - "Lisa Fox & Rhys Chatham, Institute of Contemporary Art", January 1983 (Box 5, Media ID: 249.0037)
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #249.0086.
  - [Untitled - Curt Royston], undated (Box 5, Media ID: 249.0038)
- Series V: Sound recordings
  - Hot House Rough Takes, June 1985 (Box 5, Media ID: 249.0087)
    Alternate Title: Piano Takes with Harold - 6/85
  - June Mix, 6/2/82 (Box 5, Media ID: 249.0088)
  - The Bunt, The Hunt, Floored - Swiss Mix, Feb 1982, February 1982 (Box 5, Media ID: 249.0089)